

EXPERIENCE

Nuro

Visual Designer August 2016 - Present

Lead design efforts in the company including branding, web, hardware and software UX design, video, mobile, VR, and photography · Create and develop the Nuro brand attributes and identity for internal and external use, as well as partner and consumerfacing materials · Collaborate with hardware team to test and select key components for the vehicle UX including touch display, camera, and audio equipment $\,\cdot\,$ Collaborate with software engineers to develop user-friendly interfaces for proprietary displays, internal tools, and prototype apps · Conduct internal and external user testing of vehicle UX using prototypes, VR, and finished product • Strategize with leadership and external PR firm for Nuro's public launch and announcement of first product · Storyboard, film, edit, color grade, and design visual effects for Nuro's first public-facing product launch video, receiving over 40K views in one month

Clearpath Robotics

Art Director December 2015 - July 2016

Founding member of Silicon Valley-based design team working remotely with Torontobased HQ $\,\cdot\,$ Create and develope branding identity for Clearpath and new division OTTO Motors for internal/external use and client-facing materials · Direct the design and execution of new OTTO Motors website, trade show booth, and all collateral needed for exhibition · Conceive new user-friendly interaction paradigm for client-facing tool · Collaborate with industrial designers on robot's labeling and colors

Intuitive Surgical

Senior Visual Designer February 2015 - December 2015

Prototype new visual status indicators for multiple screens on unreleased surgical device, Assist software engineers with implementation \cdot Lead UI visual design updates for da Vinci Xi Surgical System · Assist Human Factors with formative testing of new designs · Advise marketing design team on client and sales collateral · Art direct photography for internal and external marketing

Visual Designer February 2014 - February 2015

Work with Creative Director and Director of Design to develop product brand guidelines for da Vinci Xi Surgical System • Develop new user manual design to be more visual and user-friendly · Collaborate with technical publications department to integrate new design into their workflow

Clubcard

Production Manager April 2012 - February 2014

Coordinate day-to-day design and print production with the production team • Refine and maintain quality assurance standards, including preflight checklists and machine best practices · Design high-quality custom promotional material for clients and facilitated printing and delivery · Maintain and update client artwork and designs · Investigate production errors and establish procedures to prevent future errors • Outsource print work to various trade vendors \cdot Research printing stocks and media, and assist management in creating new products

Production Assistant April 2012 - May 2013

Design high quality custom promotional material for clients · Conduct preflight checks on client artwork and execute day-to-day print production · Maintain and update client artwork and designs · Outsource offset print work to various trade vendors

Copyworld

Graphic Designer June 2007 - April 2012

Design collateral for clients on a wide variety of print mediums \cdot Manage up to a dozen design projects, often under tight deadlines \cdot Conduct preflight checks on client artwork and schedule printing \cdot Develop company promotional materials for web and print \cdot Provide quotes for advanced printing orders and advise clients on best practices

CONTACT

925.497.9873 kantz.charles@gmail.com www.charleskantz.com

SUMMARY

One-man-army branding and visual designer based in San Francisco with 10 years of experience in client and in-house team environments. Experience in a wide variety of projects including branding, UX design, photo/video, and web/ mobile. Can mentor designers, lead rebranding efforts, and art direct photo and video shoots.

EDUCATION

Academy of Art University Graphic Design

San Francisco, CA - 2010 - 2013

Diablo Valley College Music

Pleasant Hill, CA - 2003 - 2006

Soft Skills

Branding, logos, typography, color theory, layout, art direction, user experience, user testing, web design. print design, UI design, interaction design, user research, motion graphics, storyboarding, filming, color correction, photo/video editing, 3D rendering, VR prototyping, HTML, CSS, C#, Communication (written and verbal), project management, problem solving, planning and organization

Tools

Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Sketch, After Effects, Lightroom, Premiere, da Vinci Resolve, Blackmagic, Nikon, Keyshot, Invision, Maya, Blender, Unity, MS Office, Google Apps, Mac, Windows.

AWARD

Rising Star Award Intuitive Surgical, 2015



PATENT

Articulable Arm With Graphical Display Intuitive Surgical, filed 2015